Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we shall give a quick overview of SDM 32 Cubitt Mix.
Okay, so my Cuba makes us open over here to create on your projects.
I can just click.
I can open existant project.
If I had existing projects, that would be listed here.
But I do not have a need.
So there's nothing here I can start to from access MSU Selecta, Access Booth Selecta or Access Cross
Selecta.
Right.
One other key point is the the tops we've got over here.
We've got a file type for new project to load project and a list of recent projects.
If we have a need, we've got a Windows type.
And this allows us to set the, um, the font size, et cetera.
And then we've got this one, this very important one to help one.
When you click on Help Top, you can check for updates.
You can manage embedded software packages.
Let's say you want to install A, B, l, e for Bluetooth low energy.
You run a store, a Bluetooth, low energy package or some other package.
You've got to come to manage embedded software packages to do that.
And you can set your user preferences by clicking over here as well.
Over here, you can give consent for data to be sent to SD microelectronics to sort of monitor the usage
of Cuba.
Makes, you know what to improve the product.
I said is written over here.
If you don't want to do that, you can simply on check this.
Right.
And, um, you can check for updates as well by clicking this.
So I'm gonna start a new project by coming over here, access to board select click here.
It's open.
It's the first time, so it's taken a while.
It's still got certain things to download, and on Zipp, it's quickly doing that.
And it's opened.
So here we are.
We've got our various development boards over here.
We've got the discovery ports.
Different types.
Cross.
Amanda Port Selector.
If I want to select just the MCU Chip, I can click over here and simply search that chip.
I'll see SDM 32 for one one and then it will list.
And when you check here, it keeps the parameter, keeps the price range as well.
Over here, the price starts from two point two eight four two three point four five.
I can reduce the price range.
If I can afford all of this to reduce the options.
These are the options that I have if I want the price to be within this range.
Right.
Because the key that makes set up from, you know, prototype into development such that you have a
clear picture of what you are dealing with over here as well.
It gives the peripherals available on a particular port.
We can filter by peripherals as well.
So what should I say?
I want.
I want to HDD and other peripherals.
I can just a neighbor determine hits enter and Cuba makes you suggest other mce use that I can use.
So let's see.
You can select by Crosswell this one.
I type this a cortex for.
That is why I just call text and voice highlighted.
I can delete this such that led to Cuba mext make that choice for me.
I'm going to select Coatex M 33 over here and it gives me the options.
These are the options and these are the peripherals available as well.
Right.
So this for the MCU selector, let's see, Harbel criticsm seven.
I've included Criticsm seven and it's increased my list and we can check for the line.
So by here, what do we want?
F one series, F zero series, et cetera.
And then.
Okay.
That's what I meant by the lines.
F one, f zero, etc..
And then the prize, the package as well.
You can select the package if you are into designing your own BCBS.
You can filter by packages as well.
Right.
So I'll just close this and then I'll come back to board selector and then I'm going to just select
the new clue F for one, one for E.T..
There is the new clue, F for one one over here.
Just double click this.
And when you highlight it, it tells you gives you the specifications of the board.
If it's obsolete, it would tell you it's obsolete.
But this is active.
Therefore, it is written at a market price.
The retail price is over here.
This is thirteen dollars and the futures of the board is listed over here or are listed over here,
I should say.
And if you want access to the data sheet as well as other documentation, you can click these tops over
here to take a look at them.
Okay.
So once I've highlighted, I can double click it or just click starts project over here like this.
And when you select a board, it would ask you, what do you want to initialize?
Or peripherals with default mode.
I'll click.
Yes.
And it's setting up the project.
Okay, so that's what it looks like.
So there's I one nuclear I see you right here.
These are the default setups and we've got the push-Button enabled for us.
We've got the LDA also set as an output pin.
And then we've got the you got to be a two and P three.
And then we've got other things with regards to the zero wire interface and the clock setters.
Okay, so this is known as the pin out of you.
We've got a pin out and configuration tab over here.
We click to set a pin.
Let's see.
I want to set it in as an output pin.
I will simply click this and select GPL output and it becomes an output pin.
Let's say I want to rename this.
All right.
Click this and see.
And to use a label, I can simply call this my output.
And then it becomes an output to be a simple cluster if I want to set it to a different type of pin.
I simply click and select the type that I want.
This is known as the.
This is known as the pin out penult and configuration view.
Right.
And I can drag a click and hold two drug to move it around.
It's allowable to do that.
I can zoom in.
I can zoom out.
I can rotate if I want.
Right.
Okay.
So there's the penult view and we have these.
So, you know, in microcontroller setup when we select a pin.
We've got to do further further configurations.
And what I mean by this is to setup to setup something like a U at a U.
Art is an alternate function on the MCU, meaning we take a GPL, your pin, and then we set it alternate
function as you got before we are able to use it.
So, for instance, if I want to say this, as you said, it's done over here after I have selected
it as U.
S.
I've got to come over here and configure its alternate function.
So under system core over here, we are given you know, we are given options to figure out what GPL
you and these often we wouldn't talk much about these.
We just explained them when we required them racc.
Over here is the bits that won't forget.
These lines are a clock high speed extend or we're not using this or we are saying bypass.
Or we can simply say disable, acyclic, disable.
You realize that this change to yellow, but I can say bypass, which is its default mode, is back
to green and low speed extend or here.
This we are using a crystal for it.
So if I disable that, you see that it's been to get disabled from here.
So as I click disable, it becomes yellow.
Right.
Yellow means you've set the GPL.
You you've got to go and do its actual alternate function configuration.
So whenever you see a pin as yellow, it's means it's setup is incomplete.
So I'll see you ceramic and then it's back to green.
Right.
And then stop over here.
The single wire.
I can disable it.
I'll show you.
That is on the other side.
I just disabled it when I see it.
Use zero wire.
It turned back to green.
Right.
And this you can do you disable the pin by selecting reset.
Okay.
Right.
And we've got Topps here for auto configuration.
If we want another configuration for our HDD, we simply click on a lock and then we select our ADC.
This MCU has a single ADC module.
But this single module has about sixteen channels.
So if we want an ATC, this is where the configuration will be done.
But we're not using an ADC now.
So ATC is under analogue.
We've got timers.
And this tab allows us to figure out various general purpose timers as well as a real time clock.
We've got connectivity as well.
This deals with things like the AI to see the SBI and the U.
S.
As we can see, the you to is setup over here.
That is why it is green and that is why we've got it correct or take over here.
So to see the configuration or to change the configuration or simply click here and you can see it says
Mode is Synchronoss and then hardware flow control disabled.
Okay.
When I disable this when I come over here mode and disable it.
When I come over here and change it or disable it, you see that these payments will be affected because
these parents are the ones connected to the U.
But let's say I go single wire, you see.
Now we've disabled.
Exline shows that the IRS is back to yellow, meaning its configuration is incomplete.
Single wire or half duplex means just one direction communication.
Go back to a Synchronoss and then this is here.
And the configuration of the actual ADC or the actual you.
I should say, is down here.
Things like the box rate we can change over here.
The word length we can change and select the pirate to the data direction, et cetera.
If we are using DME, we can click over here and add and GPL.
You, such as we know is P2, P3.
When we selected these pinions, they go added here automatically.
And whether we want to set ADC interrupt, we come to infix settings and fix stands for Nesse.
That fact or interrupt controller.
So yeah.
So connectivity provides us access to a war connectivity modules and these are the the I2 see S.P.I
and the U.
OK.
The next one is multimedia.
We have a two s over here which we can use for sound and other things.
We've got computing and we've got this module known as the CRC Mean and Cyclic Redundancy Check.
We can use that as well.
You want to add at a middle word such as a file system.
We've got futz efforts that we can include here.
We can also include a real time operating system like free our toes.
And we can include the embed tearless if we want, as well as USP devices.
Right.
So these we talk about them deeper when we are using them.
The next step up here is known as the core configuration.
So we can simply click here.
And this gives us a few of our clock.
We can, um, we can increase the clock frequency.
It says over here that Max is hundred megahertz.
So we've got to keep.
They might and we can know the proc for our various peripherals.
For instance, over here, it tells us that the plug for what time is the time is connected to the MPB
one.
The APB one bus clock currently is set at two four make a hit the clock to be called cortex system time
unassisted.
Time is clock is eighty four, etc..
So over here we have exactly the values that our farish peripherals would have for their clocks.
So let's say I want to increase the clock to one hundred.
I simply need to type one hundred here hits enter.
And it's going to configure everything appropriately.
And it's sort of arranged everything.
And over here too, we can see are using the high speed internal edge as I hear those for high speed
internal.
Remember, in our setup we said bypass high speed extend or HFC.
That is why this is selected high speed in turn on this being used.
And we are also using low speed external.
Right.
Often use in low speed extend or let's see.
Uh.
So we said no split x10, no use this ceramic, um, ceramic resonator.
And I think there is a ceramic resonator or slate.
Oh, no.
PCV on a microcontroller.
What I should say.
OK.
So that's a quick overview of the clock top.
And then, um, the next step I see to is there's this TEUs here which you use for checking the, um,
the power consumption's and other things with regards to your your board.
You find our top in the in the process is to collect the project money getup.
And over here you can give your project a name because I'll call this simple and then you can decide
on the toolchain you want to use.
So I can say I want to generate the code for SDM 32 Kupe idee, um, MBK or the other IDC if I prefer.
So this allows me to generate code for various ideas.
And you can come over here.
This is the project that's another topic called code generator.
OK.
It says the project's location cannot be empty.
So we've got to give a location for a project.
Let's see.
A crater food called Cuba makes.
Okay, so.
Right.
So let's say we want to generate projekt for SDM 30 to keep idee like this.
And then there's the code generator here.
And over here, you can take such that your files are separated into various plots, H and that C files.
I often do this or you simply take here like this.
And then once you've selected the idea you wish to use, you can simply click generate.
And it would generate it for you.
We'll see how that works when we start dealing with actual projects.
And there isn't much any more.
We can also generate a report.
Over here, we can generate a report for our setup.
Simply come to file, generate a report right here and there.
Would you like to create the project for us?
Click here.
Because the project hasn't been created yet.
OK, a report has been generated.
So I'm going to open the folder and the report comes in to form.
What does the TSD file?
As well as a PDAF encapsulating all these selections you made.
So I'm open into PDAF so that we take a look at it.
So there's the PDAF project to name and the MCU you chose as well as the date.
All of it exists.
And, um, this is the pin out.
And your clock conflagration is also included here.
As well as the other setups that you have, the RACC set up values, we find him here.
This is the art.
Everything is included here.
So this report.
Right.
So that's a quick overview of the estimated two key.
Makes five.
If you have any questions at all, just send me a message or leave in the questions area.
And I shall see you in the next lesson.
Have a nice day.